<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">John Carpenter</string>
    <string name="title_section1">About Me</string>
    <string name="title_section2">Experience</string>
    <string name="title_section3">Contact</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_title">Quick Menu</string>
    <string name="about_john_carpenter">John Carpenter</string>
    <string name="resume_title">Resume</string>

    <string name="portfolio_body" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
        <p>I would like to apply for the position of lead Android team for 37signals. I have been active in developing applications for the mobile industry for the last 10 years in a variety of capacities.&nbsp;</p><h2 style=\"margin-left:40px\">I helped co-found two startups;&nbsp;</h2><h3><strong>KnowledgeWhere ( acquired in 2008 by Liberty Media )</strong></h3><p>KnowledgeWhere started as a location-based privacy platform. In building out a demonstration of the platform capabilities, we created a multiplayer&nbsp;game to highlight how location can be used without compromising the privacy of the user. The game was well received and won a number of awards so we quickly launched a development company to produce mobile games. Blister Entertainment produced about 4 games and won numerous awards including Most Innovate Game at GDC 2008 for Blister Swordfish.&nbsp;</p><p>Later 2008 it was acquired by Liberty Media based on the strength of the platform. The games were ancillary as it was still pre-iPhone days and there was no market for mobile games.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><h3><strong>Mob4Hire</strong></h3><p>Following the success of KnowledgeWhere, I helped launch another venture called Mob4Hire. The startup addressed the problem we had with regards to testing mobile devices. Developers want to test their applications on multiple devices in multiple locations but often lacked the resources and time to do this. We created a crowdsourced platform that would pay testers from all over the world to execute test plans for the developers. This brought the cost of testing down significantly and allowed developers to rapidly launch in new markets. The site continues today with over 50,000 testers in 197 countries and hundreds of customers around the world.&nbsp;</p>
        <h2 style=\"margin-left:40px\">I work within the local startup and mobile community;</h2><p>I helped establish the local branch of MobileMonday Calgary and continue to speak at local events on a regular basis. The Calgary community is very active and growing quite quickly. I believe it is important to be active in your local community to help foster and grow the skills needed. Professionally it provides an excellent support network to be able to engage experts in an informal manner.&nbsp;</p>
        <h2 style=\"margin-left:40px\">I work on large-scale Android projects</h2><p>I have been fortunate enough to work on some very large and successful Android projects. Until Dec 2014 when it was decommissioned, <strong>Trapster </strong>was one of the largest community of drivers in the world. Having over 20MM downloads the Android application was one of the first build out onto the Google Play Store. It was acquired by <strong>NAVTEQ </strong>and later <strong>NOKIA </strong>to supplement their mapping programs. <strong>Trapster</strong> was the first to integrate <strong>NOKIA </strong>maps onto the Android platform and pushed the envelope of the devices for a number of years. Due to budgetary and organizational changes <strong>Trapster</strong> was shutdown.&nbsp;</p><p>I also helped build out the <strong>Poynt.com</strong> local search application on the Android platform. It was very popular on the Blackberry platform and porting it over allowed the number of users to grow very quickly. Since this was built on very early version (compatible to 1.5+) we had to be very careful about resource usage. We managed to built out a view lifecycle library (similar to fragments today) that effectively allowed us to customize the application to run differently on multiple devices. It sped up the development and allow us to deploy to many devices very quickly.&nbsp;</p><p>At <strong>NOKIA</strong>, I am currently working within the <a href=\"https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.here.app.maps&amp;hl=en\"><strong>HERE</strong></a> Maps team deploying the next-generation mapping tools for consumer and automotive technologies. <strong>HERE</strong> Maps is highly acclaimed and generated over a 1MM downloads in its first week. I am helping build out extensions to this application to extend the functionality to automotive and other markets.&nbsp;</p>
        <h2 style=\"margin-left:40px\">I am passionate about Android</h2><p>Android is a fascinating language with many exciting prospects. The community behind it shows a real dedication far and beyond what can be accomplished on their mobile devices. Android will provide the framework for the next generation connected devices so I am passionate about creating things with the platform. <strong><a href=\"https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.twolinessoftware.android.wemo.wemotoolkit&amp;hl=en\">WemoWay&nbsp;</a></strong>is an application I created to simplify some interactions with WeMo devices. While the community is still small they are very passionate about home automation. Me, I just wanted a better way to start my coffee machine before I wake up in the morning.&nbsp;</p>
        <h2 style=\"margin-left:40px\">Leadership and mentoring are key to any successful venture</h2><p>As much as technology expands, grows and makes things easier the key to any successful company is with its people. Having a strong culture doesn\'t mean bean-bag chairs and expensive coffee (although it doesn\'t hurt) but fostering an environment where people contribute to projects that have real direction and meaning. Having been in two CTO roles and senior architect roles I have had the opportunity to build out a number of high-performance teams and have seen what motivated and directed teams can accomplish. I would like to think that any lead role requires not only Android skills but also the skills to build out a larger Android team and community. Which is why I am passionate about 37signals. The company is always willing to take risks and build something great. After all, RoR would work great as an internal product but it shows real leadership to share those tools with the world. That attitude is a powerful motivator for people to work with you.&nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Thanks for taking the time to read this. Feel free to contact me at anytime at john@2linessoftware.com or @johncarpenter. I would be happy to discuss anything with you.&nbsp;</p><p>Cheers,&nbsp;</p><p>John</p></div>
    ]]> </string>
    <string name="contact_email">By Email</string>
    <string name="contact_twitter">Twitter</string>
    <string name="contact_title">Contact Me</string>


</resources>
